Fernando Galvan

I have made a living off building strong working-relationships with different partners, clients, coworkers, and so many more. Through those endeavors, I found my love for learning new ideas, insights and technologies. In the same amount of time, I realized that I was missing a role that allowed me to do all the things I loved. On a sleepless night, I found that software engineering had the opportunities I was seeking for so many years.

Certifications

2022-08

Current

Software Engineering, Full Stack - General Assembly Full-Stack Academy

Work History

2022-01 -

Operations Manager

- New Generations Excavation, San Antonio, TX
 Compile data to find inefficiencies to streamline our
- daily procedures within the office and field.
- Coordinate with ownership to increase buying power to reduce supply and labor cost.
- Coordinate with all stakeholders on how to further expand our footprint while maintaining the highest quality of service and production.

2021-04 -2021-12

Operations Specialist

New Generations Excavation, San Antonio, TX

- Coordinated daily schedules with different teams at all work sites while ensuring all home builder needs were met.
- Along with field supervision, I ensured certain business dealings and finances were kept to company standard.
- I kept detailed logs of completed work for billing purposes and repository purposes.

2019-10 -2021-03

Operations Coordinator

Veryable, San Antonio, Texas

• Coordinate client projects and monitor operational

Contact

Address

San Antonio, TX, 78228

Phone

210-965-5343

E-mail

n.brighter00@gmail.com

Skills

PostgreSQL

MongoDB

Node.is

ReactJS

Flask

Python

JavaScript

Training

Leadership

Risk analysis and management

Staff Management

Languages

Spanish

- performance of an on-demand platform.
- Conduct market research to optimize business development; facilitate communication as internal liaison between supply, business development, and tech development departments.
- Analyze user experience to identify operational gaps in business model as well as key marketing strategies.
- Manage social media presence to increase brand awareness and understanding of target demographics.

2017-08 - Billing Coordinator 2018-09

Envision Physician Services, San Antonio, TX

- Built and implemented a new process on how to resolve compliance deficiencies found on patient charts.
- Coordinate with different hospital departments, and providers to ensure all information is correct before sending the chart out for billing.
- I assisted in training different team members with various computer systems which included Microsoft Office.

2015-10 - Claims Analyst 2017-06

UnitedHealth Group, San Antonio, TX

- Reviewed Medicaid and Medicare claims for multiple states to ensure every claim met state and federal guidelines before financial approval.
- Was part of a specialized team which dealt with high dollar claims once reviewed by other analyst.
- Trained team members in their review and analytical processes to ensure defects decreased.

Education

2022-08 - BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

The University of Texas At San Antonio - San Antonio, TX

2015-06 - BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.S: BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

Southern New Hampshire University - San Antonio, TX